
	•	What is the setting of your game? My game takes place in a four room house  that belongs to the main characters player.The player has just woke up after a drug induced slumber. They have to find out what they missed and locate their niece. 

	•	What are some of the puzzles that you created/experimented with? Some of the puzzles that I experimented with were the Magic word system, key system, door system and combining system. I was able to get the key system down, but when I tried combining the door and combining system I had a bug. I completely removed the magic word system and will try to tackle the issue at another time.

	•	What are the two rooms? What are the three objects? Two of my main rooms are the bedroom and the kitchen. Objects that you can use include the password(I Suck), dirty clothes and a puddle of water.

	•	Please discuss, in detail, one thing you learned how to do, and how you figured it out. One thing that I learned how to do was use the door system to link and inhibit the movement of the player. I used two doors in the game, each of which were locked and required different types of puzzle solving skills to open. I found out how to use the door system from Mrs. Kiang’s advanced inform guide and the Jim Akin Handbook.

	•	What resources were most helpful to you in your learning Inform? I think that the most useful resource was probably Mrs. Kiang. In terms of her website I was able to understand a great deal about the different types of puzzles I wanted to use. Although I didn’t get to ask Mrs. Kiang personally I think that the email system in which you can personally ask her questions is extremely helpful. It seems as though the other classmates who used her were greatly helped by having her asset them. I will be sure to use her help and guidance in my final project.
	
BETA NOTES from BETA TESTERS:
Nicole Baptist:
x cosmetic(s)

x paper(s)

"I suck"

please get rid of the wiki tiki. please.

x freezer

take utensils

take oven mitts

take knife

pill is not the same as pull. i'm pretty sure you meant to say pull.
what an ending.

Kevin Miyashiro:
Hard to understand the whole combining thing.

The story seems to have a good flow

A lot of reading is required to understand the storyline

Very Frustrating when there are typos

Skylar Sang:
Very hard to read and keep up with the story

some of the descriptions did not make sense

GRAMMAR ERRORS

The ending seems sudden


Riley’s Notes and Response:

It seems as though people have a hard time when they haven’t played a interactive fiction

Many of the advanced puzzles don’t make sense to new users

People are skipping over items and missing some aspects of the game

Those who played through the whole thing by themselves said it was easy with only a key puzzle

Solution:
I tried to address most of these issues by going back into the game and proofreading all of my work. Although many people said that there was a lot of reading involved I felt as though if you take the time it is worth the amount of work you put in. I created a couple new puzzles such as the combine puzzle and the extra door so that the game didn’t feel too abrupt and end in dissatisfaction. I tried to go back and revise all of my grammatical and programming errors. I also tried to create hints that would better lead my NooB players to the answers they needed. 



